Contact

Present Address: House#18, Road#23, Pallabi, Mirpur 11.5, Dhaka-1216, Bangladesh +8801823923023 (Mobile) towfig.106@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/towfiq106 (LinkedIn)

github.com/laziestcoder (Other) towfiq.herokuapp.com (Portfolio)

Top Skills

С

C++

PHP

Languages

বাংলা (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Data Structure - Part I
Introduction to Cyber Attacks
Introduction To Python
Programming

Javascript - From Beginner to Pro-Build real world JS apps

The Data Scientist's Toolbox

Towfiqul Islam

Software Engineering Intern at Inflack Limited

Summary

"I truly love programming and enjoy debugging codes. I even code in my dreams. Coding is Love <3 "

I completed my Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering from International Islamic University Chittagong, Bangladesh. I love programming. "I truly love programming and enjoy debugging codes. I even code in my dreams. Coding is Love <3." I love to solve problems. My longest coding time is 14 hours. I can stick to a problem until it is solved. I love foods. I am fond of sweets.

I solved various types of Sports Programming Problems and different types Programming Related Problems in various online judge and my own. I know how to code in C++, PHP and Python. I know building web applications. I build several web applications using Laravel, APACHE and MySQL. I use Docker for deploying my application. I use GITHUB and BITBUCKET as VCS to track my software versions.

I was employed by Presidency International School as A-Level and O-Level Computer Science and Sports Programming Trainer for 11 months.

I am working with Inflack Limited as Software Engineering Team for R&D and serving our clients the best software.

Special Expertise : C, C++, PHP (Laravel), Python, JQuery, MySQL, Docker. Linux

Interested In: Pen-testing, Machine Learning, Cyber Security

Experience

Inflack Limited Software Engineering Intern September 2019 - Present

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Presidency International School
1 year

Permanent Computer Science Teacher April 2019 - September 2019 (6 months)

Panchlaish, Chittagong

Probationary Computer Science Teacher October 2018 - March 2019 (6 months) Panchlaish, Chittagong

Synchronise IT Intern January 2018 - July 2018 (7 months) Chittagong, Bangladesh

Education

International Islamic University Chittagong

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science and Engineering (2014 - 2019)

Govt. City College, Chittagong
Higher Secondary Certificate, Intermediate Science · (2011 - 2013)

Govt. Muslim High School, Chittagong Secondary School Certificate, Secondary Science · (2005 - 2011)